<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/industry-4.0/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-02-01T11:10:16-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/industry-4.0/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">MeruDynamics | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>The professional publishing platform</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Convolution neural network and quality control</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Convolution-neural-network-and-quality-control" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Convolution neural network and quality control" />
      <published>2019-02-01T05:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-01T05:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Convolution-neural-network-and-quality-control</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Convolution-neural-network-and-quality-control">&lt;p&gt;Quality control and assurance in manufacturing is demanding and expensive, yes, but also crucial. After all, selling flawed goods results in returns and disappointed customers. Harnessing the power of neural networks may significantly reduce the cost of visual quality control while also boosting overall process efficiency.
According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2018/03/11/10-ways-machine-learning-is-revolutionizing-manufacturing-in-2018/#3f93487723ac&quot;&gt;“Forbes”&lt;/a&gt;
, automating quality control with machine learning can increase defect detection rates up to 90%.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/ow006lzstpc0tf1/CNN.JPG?dl=0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Artificial intelligence may enhance the company’s ability to spot flawed products. Instead of embedding complex and lengthy lists of possible flaws into an algorithm, the convolutional neural network learns the product’s features. With the vision of the perfect product, the CNN can easily spot imperfect ones. The solution can learn continuously by taking feedback from manual inspectors who can review the automated classification and override them based on human judgment. The corrective information along with the image from the production floor is then included in the next training cycle for CNN model, thereby improving its ability to recognize in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Abhay</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Industry 4.0" />
      
        <category term="Artificial-Intelligence" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Quality control and assurance in manufacturing is demanding and expensive, yes, but also crucial. After all, selling flawed goods results in returns and disappointed customers. Harnessing the power of neural networks may significantly reduce the cost of visual quality control while also boosting overall process efficiency. According to “Forbes” , automating quality control with machine learning can increase defect detection rates up to 90%. Artificial intelligence may enhance the company’s ability to spot flawed products. Instead of embedding complex and lengthy lists of possible flaws into an algorithm, the convolutional neural network learns the product’s features. With the vision of the perfect product, the CNN can easily spot imperfect ones. The solution can learn continuously by taking feedback from manual inspectors who can review the automated classification and override them based on human judgment. The corrective information along with the image from the production floor is then included in the next training cycle for CNN model, thereby improving its ability to recognize in the future.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
